travelspike.com 2013-06-07

# Travel Industry, Online Marketing, Internet Destination Marketing, Tourism Advertising, Interactive Travel Experts - Travel Spike: Interactive Travel Experts

home > privacy policy 

**This Privacy Policy is effective as of** **August 10, 2009** ****

Travel Spike LLC ("TS") offers websites, web publishers and advertisers ("Partners") an advertising network which includes technology that serves online ads to consumers. 

This Privacy Policy describes TS’s privacy policies as they pertain to website visitors to our corporate website located at www.travelspike.com (our "Site"), and our targeted advertising serving technology ("Ad Technology"). 

**1\. Site Privacy Policy**

The main purpose of our company site is to offer information about TS, our network and other Internet services we provide. 

_Information Collected via the Site_   
We collect Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") from the Site when you choose to provide it to us through our contact us form or via email. PII is any information that can be used to identify or locate a particular person or entity. This includes, but is not limited to: name, postal address, telephone number, or email address. We use this personal information only to contact you to respond to your sales or marketing inquiry. Once collected, we will store your PII for a reasonable time during the course of normal business operations. _Changing / Deleting your PII_   
If you'd like us to update, correct, delete, or deactivate any PII that you have provided to us on this Site, please send your request to us at info (at) travelspike (dot) com.  We will do our best to review and process your requests within a reasonable time frame.

  **2\. Technology Privacy Policy**

 _TS's Ad Technology_   
Our Ad Technology matches TS Ads to consumers based on your interests.  Our Ad Technology collects information about the website(s) that you visit and the advertisements that you will be shown.  TS or one of our Partners may run online advertisements on a website that you visit. 

We use the information that we collect from our Ad Technology to provide reporting data as needed.

TS does not collect PII via our Technology. Our Technology does collect and use Non-PII, including: the IP address used to access the Internet, the type of browser used, which and how many Partner web pages have been viewed, search terms entered on Partner websites, referring/exit pages, and the date and time a TS Ad was viewed.  
TS uses this information to serve ads to consumers that are of interest to them as well to review web traffic patterns.  We also may review information and data in aggregate so that we can share trends or research with TS's affiliates, advertisers, employees, customers and Partners.

 _Cookies, Pixels and Web Beacons_   
A cookie stores data on a user’s hard drive on their computer.  TS uses cookies and web beacons or pixels in connection with our Technology in order to utilize retargeting. Retargeting is when TS serves a TS Ad to a user after that user has visited an Advertiser website.  Cookies help TS match a TS Ad to a user so that you will see Ads that are of interest to you.  Cookies are used by many sites and most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser using the options or preferences section to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all of the features on many sites that you visit.

TS also uses web beacons to review web traffic data. The use of a web beacon allows TS to record that someone has visited a particular webpage, along with additional Non-PII that the website may choose to include with the beacon.

 _Data Relating to Non-PII_  
We keep the Non-PII collected via our Ad Technology for up to 90 days in order to make sure that our Technology is working. After 90 days, we may store the data anonymously to be used in aggregate in the future. _Opting out_   
If you'd like to opt-out from having TS collect your Non-PII in connection with our Ad Technology, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or email us at info (at) travelspike (dot) com. When you opt out, we will place an opt-out cookie on your computer. The opt-out cookie tells us not to collect your Non-PII and not to tailor TS Ads to your interests. You may need to opt-out again if you delete your cookies or modify your cookie options after you have opted-out.  Cookies are specific to a computer, so you may also need to opt out again if you use a separate computer or browser. 

**3\. Miscellaneous:**

 _Security_

TS takes the security of your information very seriously. We have put in place security measures to protect the information so that data is kept safe and confidential. 

_Information Relating to Children_

TS Ads and products are designed for those over the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect PII from anyone under the age of 18. If we are made aware that we have received PII from someone under 18, we will use reasonable efforts to remove that information from our records.

 _Disclosure of Information to Third Parties_

TS does not sell, trade, rent, or release your personal information to third parties in ways that are not disclosed in the privacy statement. If we were to ever do so, you will have the opportunity to Opt-Out beforehand. 

We do not collect PII via our Technology, and we do not sell, rent or share PII collected on the Website with non-affiliated third parties without your consent. We may, however, share your PII with trusted third party contractors who provide services for us. These third party contractors are prohibited from using the information we provide for purposes other than performing services for us.

We may share Non-PII collected via our Technology with Web Partners. 

_Changes to this Privacy Policy_

This privacy policy is subject to change at any time.  We will notify you on our website on the privacy policy page or via email.

 _3rd Party Website’s Policies_

TS has no control over, nor does it bear any of the responsibility for the privacy policies and/or content of any sites, Partners or advertisers within the Travel Ad Network® or linked to from TravelSpike.com, or the cookies these sites might deposit on your hard drive. 

TS is in compliance of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI").
